schlundtech.com 2011-04-30

# schlund technologies

It is essential for us to collect, store and process data, or make it usable in other ways, so that we can provide our full services to you. Yet, in order to protect your customer data we have the duty to follow a number of guidelines and regulations. We therefor want to inform you about how we guarantee for the protection of the data you entrust to us. 

Collection, processing and use of your personal data by Schlund Technologies is in strict compliance with German data protection laws. At the moment, this implicates the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG),the German Telemedia Act (TMG) and the German Telecommunications Act (TKG). Data processing, collection and storage of data is indispensable for us in order to enter into, exchange or carry out business relations.

We use this data, as far as it is inevitable for us to fulfil the obligations of these business relations. On the other hand, we only use your personal data, e.g. for purposes of advertisement, market research or for the creation of user profiles, if we receive an explicit authorization of our customers. Even then our customers have the right to withdraw their authorization at any time. 

Processing and using customer data is only legal, if it happens on an anonymous basis. This means, it has to be used in a manner where no further information to identify the respective person can be drawn from the data being processed. 

To ensure proper billing of the services rendered to you on a user dependent basis, we of course require the use of respective customer data. Likewise, in order to be able to register domain names, it is necessary for us to pass on certain data to registry organizations. Sometimes, this data is publicly accessible through databases (so called whois databases). Partly, this data is forwarded to RIPE NCC in the Netherlands, who also manages public databases on the internet. According to the legal regulations of RIPE, static IP addresses can only be distributed if personal data of the respective customer has been provided to RIPE before. 

Apart from that, the communication of your personal data to third parties only takes place if Federal Data Protection Law permits this. The same conditions apply, if you register for any other service on our webpage (e.g. online application, Callback-Service) or, if you pass on personal information to us in any other way. Your data will only be used if it is necessary to accomplish our services.

As a means to control our data protection regulations on an individual basis, you have a right to information at all times. For example, you have the opportunity to request information from Schlund Technologies and inquire, if personal data of you or your co-workers has been stored. You may also ask for what means this data was processed and to which institutions it has been transferred. You can object to the use of your personal data at any time.

Last but not least, we want to stress that it is likely that inapplicable data is stored in our database, if you (or your customers) have not informed us about personal data changes. 

Let us therefor all work together, to facilitate the application of data protection laws and regulations in practice!
